Kircheimer, Otto; Papers ger006
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Professional Correspondence, 1927-1965; 2; 186 file folders
  - Triesch, Günter (Deutsches Industrieinstitut), 1961-1962 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 33)
  - Truman, David B. (Columbia University), 1960-1963 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 34)
  - Turner, John E., 1964 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 35)
  - The United States National Commission for UNESCO (Thomas L. Nicholson), 1963 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 36)
  - von der Heydte, Freiherr, 1956-1957 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 37)
  - von Eynern, Gert, 1960-1963 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 38)
  - W -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 39)
  - Wald, Edu, 1959 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 40)
  - Warnecke, Steven, 1964-1965 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 41)
  - Weinert, Richard, 1963 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 42)
  - White, Howard B., 1960-1962; Undated (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 43)
  - Wolff, Kurt H., 1965 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 44)
  - Wormuth, Francis D., 1959-1964 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 45)
  - Yale University, 1962-1963 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 46)
  - Zahn, Gordon C., 1962 (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 47)
  - Letter fragments, Undated (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 48)
  - Unidentified letters, Undated (Box 2 (2-Professional Correspondence), Folder 49)
- Correspondence with Publishers, 1952-1965; 3; 25 file folders
  Includes correspondence with University of Chicago Press, Princeton University Press and Luchterhand Verlag.
  - The American Political Science Review, 1961-1965 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 50)
  - The American Political Science Review (Harvey C. Mansfield), 1957-1965 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 51)
  - The Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1962 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 52)
  - Bund Verlag, 1955; 1960 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 53)
  - Encyclopedic Dictionary, 1964 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 54)
  - Gewerkschaftliche Umschau (Kurt Brumlop), 1963-1964 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 55)
  - Harcourt, Brace & World, Inc., 1963-1965 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 56)
  - Hermann Luchterhand Verlag (Frank Benseler), 1957-1965 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 57)
  - International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1963 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 58)
  - J.C.B. Mohr (Paul Siebeck), Tübingen, 1960-1962 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 59)
  - Neue Politische Literatur (F. A. Krummacher), 1956-1964 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 60)
  - New York Times, 1964-1965 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 61)
  - Political Science Quarterly, 1962-1965 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 62)
  - Prager, Frederick A., Inc., 1962 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 63)
  - Princeton University Press, 1960 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 64)
  - Princeton University Press, 1961-1964 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 65)
  - Social Research, 1960 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 66)
  - Stanford University Press, 1965 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 67)
  - Suhrkamp-Verlag (Günther Busch), 1961-1965 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 68)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1958-1960 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 69)
  - The Washington Post, 1959-1965 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 70)
  - Westdeutscher Verlag, 1961-1964 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 71)
  - World Politics, 1957; 1960; 1963 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 72)
  - Yale Law Journal, 1952; 1958; 1960 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 73)
  - Publishers -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 2 (3-Correspondence with Publishers), Folder 74)
- Writings, 1937-1964; 4; 28 file folders
  Compositions: Contains hand corrected typescripts and carbon copies of Political Justice as well as typescripts and offprints of several articles and essays.
  Book Reviews: Includes book reviews written 1937-1939 during Kirchheimer's exile in Paris and New York, as well as reviews written for the Washington Post and American Political Science Review. These cover a broad range of topics, including the Weimar Republic, German politics since 1933, national socialism, Marxism, the post-war government of Germany, modern French history, French foreign politics, as well as Catholics and Jews in Germany.
  - "The Act, the Offense and Double Jeopardy", 1949; offprint (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 75)
  - "Asylum", 1959; offprint (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 76)
  - "Bemerkungen zu Carl Schmitts 'Legalitaet und Legitimitaet'", Undated; offprint (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 77)
  - "Confining Conditions and Revolutionary Breakthroughs", 1965; offprint (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 78)
  - "Deutschland oder Der Verfall der Opposition", 1966; offprint (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 79)
  - "Elite - Consent - Control in the Western Political System", 1964 October; typescript, copy (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 80)
  - "European Parliaments", 1963; typescript, copy (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 81)
  - Fragments, Undated (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 82)
  - German Elections, 1952; corrected typescript (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 83)
    With letter from Sigmund Neumann.
  - "Gewerkschaften und Politik in der USA", 1964(?); corrected typescript (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 84)
  - "Die Justiz", 1964; typescript (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 85)
  - "Die Lehre von Stettin", Undated; copy (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 86)
  - "El Ocaso de la Oposicion en el Regimen Parlamentario", Undated (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 87)
  - "The Party in Mass Society", 1958; offprint (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 88)
  - "Personalization and Concentration of Power: Are They Consistent with Democracy?" (carbon), 1963 (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 89)
  - "The Policy of the Catholic Church Toward the Jews" (carbon), Undated (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 90)
  - Political Justice, 1962; typescripts, carbons, thermofaxes (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 91)
  - "Political Justice" - article, 1962; corrected copy (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 92)
  - "Private Man and Society", 1966; corrected typescript and offprint (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 93)
  - "The Realities of Political Responsibility: Parliament and Party in Western Europe" (outline), Undated (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 94)
  - "The Rechtstaat as a Magic Wall", 1965; draft typescript (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 95)
  - "Son compatibles con la democracia la personalizacion y la concentracion del poder?", 1962(?); offprint (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 96)
  - "The Transformation of the European Party System", 1964; draft and offprint (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 97)
  - "Die Transformierung des Westeuropaeischen Parteisystems", Undated (Box 2 (4-Writings), Folder 97)
  - Untitled Articles - typescripts and carbons, Undated (Box 3 (4-Writings), Folder 1)
  - "Vorbemerkung", 1964 Fall; corrected typescript (Box 3 (4-Writings), Folder 2)
  - "Der Wandel des Westeuropaeisches Parteisystems", 1965; offprint (Box 3 (4-Writings), Folder 3)
  - "The Waning of Opposition", Undated; offprint (Box 3 (4-Writings), Folder 4)
  - "Warum ich nicht in der Bundesrepublik lebe" (carbon), 1962 (Box 3 (4-Writings), Folder 5)
  - "Zuchthaus Untermassfeld und moderne Presseberichterstattung", Undated; corrected typescript (Box 3 (4-Writings), Folder 6)
  - Book Reviews - Early Reviews, 1937-1939; copies (Box 3 (4-Writings), Folder 7)
  - Book Reviews - Reviews for Washington Post, 1960-1963; copies (Box 3 (4-Writings), Folder 8)
  - Book Reviews - Reviews, 1936-1964; typescripts (Box 3 (4-Writings), Folder 9)
- Kirchheimer's Testimony before the House Foreign Affairs Committee, 1964 June 29; 5; 1 file folder
  "The Wall and After" - Discusses the relationship between East and West Germany.
  - Testimony before House Foreign Affairs Committee, 1964 June 29 (Box 3 (5-Kirchheimer's Testimony before the House Foreign A), Folder 10)
- Reviews of Kirchheimer's Publications, 1939-1965; 6; 4 file folders
  Arranged by title.
  - Reviews of Punishment and Social Structure, Undated (Box 3 (6-Reviews of Kirchheimer's Publications), Folder 11)
  - Reviews of Political Justice, Undated (Box 3 (6-Reviews of Kirchheimer's Publications), Folder 12)
  - Reviews of Politische Justiz, Undated (Box 3 (6-Reviews of Kirchheimer's Publications), Folder 13)
  - Other Reviews of Kirchheimer Publications, Undated (Box 3 (6-Reviews of Kirchheimer's Publications), Folder 14)
- Teaching and Research Notes, Undated; 7; 15 file folders
  Includes handwritten notes by Kirchheimer on Constitutional Law, Parliamentarianism, Comparative Government, and European Political Institutions, as well as lecture notes taken by his students.
  - Lecture notes, reading lists, exams, ca. 1960-1964 (Box 3 (7-Teaching and Research Notes), Folder 15)
  - Lecture notes taken by a student, Undated (Box 3 (7-Teaching and Research Notes), Folder 16)
  - Lecture notes (?), Undated (Box 3 (7-Teaching and Research Notes), Folder 17)
  - Handwritten notes labeled 1-149, Undated (Box 3 (7-Teaching and Research Notes), Folder 18)
  - Notebook "I", Undated (Box 3 (7-Teaching and Research Notes), Folder 19)
  - Notebook "II", Undated (Box 3 (7-Teaching and Research Notes), Folder 20)
  - Notebook "III", Undated (Box 3 (7-Teaching and Research Notes), Folder 21)
  - Notebook "IV", Undated (Box 3 (7-Teaching and Research Notes), Folder 22)
  - Notebook (unlabeled), Undated (Box 3 (7-Teaching and Research Notes), Folder 23)
  - Notebooks (unlabeled), Undated (Box 3 (7-Teaching and Research Notes), Folder 24)
  - Notebook "Constitutional Law", Undated (Box 3 (7-Teaching and Research Notes), Folder 25)
  - Notebook "Deutscher Strafrecht", Undated (Box 3 (7-Teaching and Research Notes), Folder 26)
  - Notebook (political trials?), Undated (Box 3 (7-Teaching and Research Notes), Folder 27)
  - Handwritten notes, 1964-1965 (Box 3 (7-Teaching and Research Notes), Folder 28)
  - Handwritten notes, ca. 1965 (Box 3 (7-Teaching and Research Notes), Folder 29)
- Research Materials, Undated; 8; 18 file folders
  Contains annotated constitutions and laws, newspaper clippings, legal briefs and other publications, many of which are heavily annotated by Kirchheimer. These include the 1963 German "Spiegel" case and the Morton Sobell case. There are also annotated Marxist-Leninist pamphlets.
  - Constitutions and Laws - East Germany, Undated (Box 3 (8-Research Materials), Folder 30)
  - Constitutions and Laws - Prussia and West Germany, Undated (Box 3 (8-Research Materials), Folder 31)
  - Constitutions and Laws -- Switzerland, Undated (Box 3 (8-Research Materials), Folder 32)
  - Constitutional Complaint: Der Spiegel Case, 1963 (Box 4 (8-Research Materials), Folder 1)
  - Criminal Procedure Bill - Israel, 1959 (Box 4 (8-Research Materials), Folder 2)
  - Federal Legislation - Germany, 1953-1957 (Box 4 (8-Research Materials), Folder 3)
  - German Court Case: Hedler, 1950 (Box 4 (8-Research Materials), Folder 4)
  - Die Justiz: Photocopies with Annotations - Band I, II, Undated (Box 4 (8-Research Materials), Folder 5)
  - Die Justiz: Photocopies with Annotations - Band III, IV, Undated (Box 4 (8-Research Materials), Folder 6)
  - Die Justiz: Photocopies with annotations - Band V, VI, Undated (Box 4 (8-Research Materials), Folder 7)
  - Die Justiz: Photocopies with Annotations - Band VII, VIII, Undated (Box 4 (8-Research Materials), Folder 8)
  - Law Briefs: Gedeon vs. East Ohio Gas Company; Preston vs. Dorman; Alexander Auto vs. Pedes, 1928-1932 (Box 4 (8-Research Materials), Folder 9)
  - Morton Sobell Case, Undated (Box 4 (8-Research Materials), Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Undated (Box 4 (8-Research Materials), Folder 11)
  - Pamphlets: Marxist-Leninist, Undated (Box 4 (8-Research Materials), Folder 12)
  - Publications: U.S. Government - Europe, 1953 (Box 4 (8-Research Materials), Folder 13)
  - Publications: U.S. Government - Israel, Undated (Box 4 (8-Research Materials), Folder 14)
  - Socialist Party - East Germany, Undated (Box 4 (8-Research Materials), Folder 15)
- Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues, 1913-1964; 9
  Political, economic and social issues addressed by Kirchheimer's colleagues. Includes typescripts and offprints, arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Arndt, Adolf. "Empfiehlt es sich, die vollständige Selbstverwaltung aller Gerichte im Rahmen des Grundgesetzes gesetzlich einzuführen?", Undated; offprint (Box 4 (9-Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues), Folder 16)
  - Fraenkel, Ernst. "'Martial Law' und Staatsnotstand in England und USA", 1965; offprint (Box 4 (9-Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues), Folder 17)
  - Friesenhahn, Ernst. "Die Völkerrechtliche und Staatsrechtliche Lage Deutschlands, Undated; offprint (Box 4 (9-Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues), Folder 18)
  - Goldstein, Abraham. "The State and the Accused: Balance of Advantage in Criminal Procedure", 1960; offprint (Box 4 (9-Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues), Folder 19)
  - Goldstein, Joseph. "Police Discretion not to Invoke the Criminal Process: Low-visibililty Decisions in the Administration of Justice", 1960; offprint (Box 4 (9-Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues), Folder 20)
  - Gurland, A. R. L. "Wirtschaft und Gesellschaft im Übergang zum Zeitalter der Industrie", Undated; offprint (Box 4 (9-Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues), Folder 21)
  - Lewalter, Ernst. "Wissenssoziologie und Marxismus. Eine Auseinandersetzung mit Karl Mannheims 'Ideologie und Utopie' von marxistischer Position aus", Undated; offprint (Box 4 (9-Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues), Folder 22)
  - Lichtblau, George E. "The World Federation of Trade Unions", Undated; mimeographed typescript (Box 4 (9-Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues), Folder 23)
  - Lorwin, Val R., Undated (Box 4 (9-Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues), Folder 24)
    "Syndicats et action politique aus Etats-Unis" (offprint, 1963); "Working-Class Politics and Economic Development in Western Europe" (offprint, 1958); 2 reviews (typescripts).
  - Marcuse, Herbert. "An Introduction to Hegel's Philosophy", 1940; offprint (Box 4 (9-Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues), Folder 25)
  - Miguel, Amando de y Linz, Juan J. "Nivel de Estudios del Emprisariado Espanol, 1964; offprint (Box 4 (9-Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues), Folder 26)
  - Neumann, Franz L. "Die Diktatur"; "Zur Theorie der Diktatur", Undated; typescripts (Box 4 (9-Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues), Folder 27)
  - Sawyer, John E. "Strains in the Social Structure of Modern France", 1951; offprint (Box 4 (9-Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues), Folder 28)
  - Schmid, Richard. "Wie frei sind Meinung und Meldung?", Undated; offprint (Box 4 (9-Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues), Folder 29)
  - Schmitt, Carl. "Der Hüter der Verfassung", 1929; offprint (Box 4 (9-Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues), Folder 30)
  - Smend, Rudolf, Undated (Box 4 (9-Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues), Folder 31)
    "Der Einfluß der deutschen Staats- und Verwaltungsrechtslehre des 19. Jahrhunderts auf das Leben in Verfassung und Verwaltung" (offprint, 1939); "Politisches Erlebnis und Staatsdenken seit dem 18. Jahrhundert" (offprint, 1943).
  - Weber, Werner. "Parlamentarische Unvereinbarkeiten (Inkompatibilitäten)", Undated; offprint (Box 4 (9-Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues), Folder 32)
  - Welles, C. Bradford. "Die Hellenistische Welt", Undated; offprint (Box 4 (9-Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues), Folder 33)
  - Westin, Alain F. "Politics in Europe: 5 Cases in European Government", Undated; typescript (Box 4 (9-Writings by Kirchheimer's Professional Colleagues), Folder 34)
- Political pamphlets, 1913-1969; 10; 54 file folders
  Contains pamphlets authored by colleagues of Kirchheimer, as well as a number of speech texts.
  - Albrecht, Karl.Patterns of Economic Integration, 1951 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 1)
  - American Civil Liberties Union."Testing Whether That Nation": 41st Annual Report. July 1, 1960-June 30, 1961, Undated (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 2)
  - Bader, Karl Siegfried.Die deutschen Juristen, 1947 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 3)
  - Barth, Karl.Offenbarung, Kirche, Theologie. Schriftenreihe Theologische Existenz Heute, Heft 9, 1934 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 4)
  - Barth, Karl.Theologische Existenz Heute. 8th ed. Schriftenreihe Theologische Existenz Heute, Heft 1, 1933 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 5)
  - Baumgarten, Arthur.Demokratie und Rechtstaat in der Neuzeit, 1946 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 6)
  - Berlin, Isaiah.Two Concepts of Liberty, 1958 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 7)
  - Bloch, Ernst.Differenzierungen im Begriff Fortschritt. Sitzungsberichte der Deutschen Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin, 2. Auflage, 1957 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 8)
  - Breuner, Otto.Das Aktions-Programm, 1956 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 9)
  - Brodie, William.Manual for Kings County Grand Jurors, 1960 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 10)
  - Bundestagung der Sozialausschuesse der christlich-demokratischen Arbeitnehmerschaft: Von der Sozialpolitik zur Sozialreform. Koeln, 1953 February 28-1953 March 1 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 11)
  - Constitution (Fundamental Law) of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, 1936 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 12)
  - Crossman, R. H. S.Labour in the Affluent Society, 1960 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 13)
  - Erler, Aldalbert, Hg.Quellen zur deutschen Verfassungsgeschichte von Otto II bis zu Ludwig dem Bayern, 1913 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 14)
  - Fechner, Erich.Die Soziologische Grenze der Grundrechte, 1954 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 15)
  - Flechtheim, Ossip K.Politik als Wissenschaft, 1953 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 16)
  - Fraenkel, Ernst. Korea: ein Wendepunkt im Voelkerrecht?, 1951 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 17)
  - Fraenkel, Osmond K.The Supreme Court and Civil Liberties: How Far has the Court Protected the Bill of Rights?, 1955 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 18)
  - Friesenhahn, Ernst.Staatsrechtslehre und Verfassung, 1950 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 19)
  - Götting, Gerald.Wie entstehen unsere Gesetze?, 1960 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 20)
  - Der grosse Streik in der hessischen Metallindustrie.Schriftenreihe der Industriegewerkschaft Metall fuer die Bundesrepublik Deutschland, 1951 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 21)
  - Güde, Max.Justiz im Schatten von Gestern, 1958 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 22)
  - Guérin, Daniel.Quand le fascisme nous devançcait: Souvenirs et Leçons de dix ans 1930-1940, 1955 (Box 5 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 23)
  - Hallstein, Walter.Wiederherstellung des Privatrechts, 1946 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 1)
  - Hennis, Wilhelm.Deutscher Widerstand 1933-1945; Schmidt, Dietrich. Der Kirchliche Widerstand, 1965 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 2)
  - Heuss, Theodor.Die deutsche Nationalidee im Wandel der Geschichte, 1946 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 3)
  - Hildebrand, Dietrich von.Die Sittlichen Grundlagen der Völkergemeinschaft, 1946 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 4)
  - International Commission of Jurists.The Rule of Law in the Federal Republic of Germany, 1958 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 5)
  - Hüttenwerk Salzgitter AG.Wir...und die Hütte, Undated (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 6)
  - Keller, Peter.Grundfragen der Arbeitsbewertung, 1949 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 7)
  - Laski, Harold J.Justice and the Law, 1930 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 8)
  - Lassalle, Ferdinand.Über Verfassungswesen, 1926 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 9)
  - Leibholz, Gerhard.Demokratie und Rechtsstaat, 1957 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 10)
  - Leibholz, Gerhard.Die Strukturwandel der modernen Demokratie, 1952 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 11)
  - Leibholz, Gerhard.Volk, Nation und Staat im 20. Jahrhundert, 1958 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 12)
  - Lenin, W. I.Ein Vortrag ueber die Revolution von 1905, 1946 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 13)
  - Mao Tse-Tung.Über die Diktatur der Volksdemokratie, 1951 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 14)
  - Mao Tse-Tung.Why can China's Red Political Power Exist?, 1953 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 15)
  - Mussolini, Benito.The Political and Social Doctrine of Fascism, 1933 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 16)
  - Plechanow, G. W.Über materialistische Geschichtsauffassung, 1946 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 17)
  - Posser, Diether.Politische Strafjustiz aus der Sicht des Verteidigers, 1961 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 18)
  - Riezler, Kurt.Über Gebundenheit und Freiheit des gegenwärtigen Zeitalters, 1929 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 19)
  - Rischin, Moses."Our Own Kind": Voting by Race, Creed or National Origin, 1960 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 20)
  - Robertus, Carl.Die Forderungen der arbeitenden Klassen, 1944 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 21)
  - Salomon, Ernst von.Putsch. Schriftenreihe Das Reich im Werden: Arbeitshefte im Dienste politischer Erziehung, herausgegeben von Dr. Rudolf Ibel, 1933 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 22)
  - Schmitt, Carl.Die Tyrannei der Werte, 1960 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 23)
  - Social Democratic Party of Germany.Basic Programme of the Social Democratic Party of Germany, 1959 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 24)
  - Speier, Hans.Soviet Atomic Blackmail and the North Atlantic Alliance. U.S. Air Force Project Rand Research Memorandum, 1956 December 10 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 25)
  - Steiniger, Peter A.Vom Wesen unserer Arbeiter- und Bauernmacht, 1954 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 26)
  - Strauss, Herbert A., ed.Conference on Anti-Semitism, 1969 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 27)
  - The United States Stategic Bombing Survey: Summary Report (European War), 1945 September 30 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 28)
  - Die Verfassung der Deutschen Demokratischen Republik, 1949 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 29)
  - Weber, Max.Wissenschaft als Beruf, 1921 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 30)
  - Wilhelm, Theodor.Die Idee des Berufsbeamtentums, 1933 (Box 6 (10-Political pamphlets), Folder 31)